Guide to the Houston Electric Auto Association Records 2016-047
University of Houston Libraries Special Collections
Houston Electric Auto Association Records
1973-2011
1995-2006
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Houston Electric Auto Association; Brooks, Dale, 1954-2014
2016-047
2.00 Linear Feet
This collection includes the organization's correspondence with the government and members' correspondence amongst themselves, as well as announcements of meetings and different events that they held occasionally. It also includes electric battery review booklets plus articles showing the organization and members' various achievements.
Acquisition Information:
Donated by Ella Tyler, December 12, 2016
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes the organization's correspondence with the government and members' correspondence amongst themselves, as well as announcements of meetings and different events that they held occasionally. It also includes electric battery review booklets plus articles showing the organization and members' various achievements.
Included are photographs of various occasions hosted or attended by the Houston Electric Auto Association members, brochures showing different clean sources of energy and business cards of some of the people that the members associated with. This collection also contains interviews of the organization's various members stored on different types of media like compact discs (CDs) and Video Home System (VHS). Materials in this collection are arranged chronologically within the series.
Business cards; Clippings (information artifacts); Compact discs; Correspondence; Interviews; Photographs; Battery charging stations (Electric vehicles); Electric Vehicles; Hydrogen as fuel
- Correspondence and Documentation
  Scope and Contents
  Assorted records of communication with and within the organization alongside documentation that shows different facets of the organization.
  - Houston Electric Auto Association (HEAA) correspondence
    Communication with and within the organization.
    - Correspondence, 1990-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Electric Car Documentation
    International and national newsletters from different electric organizations. Meeting announcements and different articles showing the organization's achievements.
    - Articles and Newsletters, 1990-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Battery Reviews, 2000-2005 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Electric Vehicle Components, 1996-2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Meeting Announcements, 2002-2009 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Ephemera
  Miscellaneous items and objects associated with the daily running of the organization.
  - Ephemera, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Houston Electric Auto Association Hats, undated (Ovs box 5)
  - Electric Auto Association Hat, undated (Ovs box 5)
  - Press Coverage, 1993-2008 (Ovs box 5, Folder 1)
- Media
  - Photographs
    - 1995-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Electric Vehicle (EV) Photos, undated (Box 4)
  - Compact Discs (CDs)
    Compact discs with different material concerning the organization.
    - Frank Zappa Interview, March 1973 (Box 3)
    - Earth Day, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Ken's 86 Birthday, May 2006 (Box 3)
    - Now – Who Killed The Electric Car?, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Who Killed The Electric Car?, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Daily Show: Chris Payne - Who Killed The Electric Car?, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Electric Vehicle (EV), 2006 (Box 3)
    - Earth Day, 2006 (Box 3)
    - Electrica/Electravan Safari, 2007 (Box 3)
    - The Progressive Forum, Guest - Dale Brooks, 2008 (Box 3)
    - Zenn & Zap n EWN@ Sam, 2009 (Box 3)
    - Houston Electric Auto Association (HEAA) on KTRK-TV, 2009 (Box 3)
    - Electric Dreams - 1990s, 2011 (Box 3)
    - National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) 4, NOVA Electric Vehicles (EVs), NOW, 2011 (Box 3)
    - Tango News Stories, undated (Box 3)
    - Motorweek - Future Cars, undated (Box 3)
    - Green Wheels, undated (Box 3)
    - Electric Scooter Vectrix, undated (Box 3)
    - Electric Vehicles (EVs) are here... Are you ready?, undated (Box 3)
    - Electric Auto Association Electric Vehicles (EAAEV.ORG – convert it), undated (Box 3)
    - KPFT-FM Progressive Forum, undated (Box 3)
  - Videotapes (VHS)
    Videotape cassettes with different interviews of organization members.
    - Dale Brooks, KHOU-TV News, March 2000 (Box 4)
    - Dale Brooks, KPFT News, June 2011 (Box 4)
    - Dale Brooks, KHOU-11 News (Betacam), undated (Box 4)
    - Ben Chamberlain, Eyewitness News, undated (Box 4)
    - Omnibus, Electric Vehicles (Omnibus EV), undated (Box 4)
    - Hydrogen - the safe and clean fuel, udnated (Box 4)